

23 year old Electronics & Telecommunication Engineer studying Packaging, identities and systems design at Pratt Institute in Brooklyn, New York. Currently exploring and looking for opportunities in the field of design. Curiously investigating the interactions between people and technologies with a multi-disciplinary approach.

kshitijnileshshah@gmail.com kshah45@pratt.edu +1 347 588 9028

GPA: 3.925/4

#### **EDUCATION -**

# K.J. Somaiya College of Engineering, Mumbai

Bachelor of Technology, Electronics & Telecommunication Engineering

Aug 2017 - May 2022

#### Pratt Institute, New York

MS Packaging, Identities & Systems Design

Aug 2022 - May 2024

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Visual Designer - Creative Varchasv

Sept 2022 - April 2022

Leading a team of three designers to design various cross platform experiences and UI kits for clients. The work ranges from brand marketing collaterals to website user interfaces for brands like Dyson, Taj, Red Bull, Nestle Coca Cola, Casio, Emerald lewellers and so on.

#### **VOLUNTEERING** —

### IXDA 2021 - Design Volunteer

February 2021

Remotely moderated chat rooms and Q&A sessions at the International conference.

### DataZen Somaiya Vidyavihar - Creative Head

February 2021 - May 2022

Leading a team of 3 visual designers to create content for the official data science club of Somaiya Vidyavihar.

#### KISCE Students Council - Creative Head

June 2018 - June 2020

Organised various festivals & events for the college & designed publicity collaterals along with brand marketing to get sponsors on board.

### TEDxSomaiyaVidyaVihar - Graphic Designer

June 2018 - June 2020

Organised various festivals & events for the college & designed publicity collaterals.

### Manchester City Mumbai SC - Graphic Designer

April 2020 - ongoing

Designed various marketing collaterals, t-shirts for Manchester City Mumbai Official Supporters Club recognized by Manchester City Football Club, Manchester, UK.

### Pritam Arts Screenprinting Studio - Volunteer

December 2021

Was chosen as the volunteer at Pritam Arts Screenprinting Studio based in Mumbai, India. The goal was to teach design enthusiasts, the basics of screen printing in batches of 15.

## Lil Flea' 2023 - Guest Speaker

January 2023

Was invited as a guest speaker to give some insights into the packaging industry in the United States in one of the biggest art festivals in Mumbai, India in collaboration with Pritam Arts Screenprinting studio.

### **PROJECTS**

## Kshitij Magazine - Art Director

Led a team of 6 visual artists to design the college periodical. Created marketing campaigns which led to a well received 2019 edition with over 3500 copies printed.

# KJSCE Yearbook 2020/2021 -Lead Designer

April 2020 & April 2021

Took an initiative to design yearbooks for the passing batches of the year 2020 and 2021 which were received immense happiness.

# The Lucid Dream - Logo Designer

June 2020

Made a comprehensive logo for The Lucid Dream, an Indie-Rock band based in Mumbai, India.

## **Emerald Jewellers - Branding**

August 2021

Led the branding campaign for Emerald lewellers for their exhibition in the Indian International Jewellery Show (IIJS).

#### **INTERESTS**

Typography Design Research **Branding** Visual Design User Interface Design Packaging Design Gaming **Photography** 

### **TOOLS**

Adobe Suite Figma Rhino Form Z AutoCAD Blender

CorelDraw MS Office Suite Basics of HTML/CSS Basics of C++/Java

Asana Shapr 3D

behance.net/kshitijsha2e21 linkedin.com/in/kshitijshah17/ instagram.com/kshitijshah17/